狂気のふちを行くゲーム Ｅカード
E-Card, a game heading
towards an abyss of insanity.
A big bet was placed just before
the final round.
その最終戦を前にした大勝負
持たざる者 カイジ
Kaiji finally makes his move
against the old fox, Tonegawa!
ついに 老かい利根川を討つ
そして
血の代償と引き換えに得る大金
He gives his blood in exchange
for a huge sum of 11.1 million!
1110万円
勝負は決したかに見えた
It seemed that the battle
was finally over.
But Kaiji had an intuitive flash!
しかし カイジを貫く
ある ひらめき
I can win the 12th round too!
勝てる 12戦目も
もう一度 18ミリだ
I'll bet 18 mm
in another round!
もう一度 生き死にの ばくち
One more life-or-death gamble!
The insanity is not yet over!
狂気の沙汰は まだ終わらない
Heart's Blood
な… 何言いだすんですか
カイジさん
W-What are you trying to do,
Kaiji?!
今の勝ちだって奇跡的なのに
It was already a miracle
for you to win!
もう十分じゃないですか
もう次は ないっすよ
Isn't that enough?
There won't be a next time!
ほっとけ
Leave me alone!
カイジさん
Kaiji!
勝ち運に乗ってるここで
下がれるか
I can't back down when
luck is on my side!
When will I ever
get such a chance?
今行かずに どうするんだよ
むちゃですよ
うるせえ
Don't be reckless!
Shut up, just get me a towel!
それより タオルだ
タオルをもう１本 持ってこい
Bring me another towel!
カ… カイジさん
Kaiji...
早くしろ！
Hurry and get it!
Hey!
おい
この ばかが
This idiot...
He's getting too full
of himself.
調子に乗りおって
何が もう一度
生き死にの ばくちだ
What's with another
life-or-death gamble?
Wonderful...
This is wonderful, indeed!
すばらしい
実に すばらしい
You only have one life.
命は １つしかない
だから大切にせよと みんな言う
That's why everybody tells
you to treasure it.
親も教師も
Your parents and teachers...
The commentators who
appear on TV...
テレビに出てくる
見識者とかいう やから
Even the musicians say so.
果ては ミュージシャンまでもが
言う
命は大切にせよとのう
You should cherish
your life.
That's why you shouldn't
follow their advice!
だから 駄目なのだ
命は もっと粗末に扱うべきなのだ
Your life should be
thrown around!
It'll stagnate and rot if
you over protect it.
命というやつは
丁寧に扱い過ぎると
よどみ 腐る
People nowadays care about
themselves too much.
最近のやからは
皆 己を大事にしすぎて
As a result, they can't grasp
any opportunities,
結果 チャンスをつかむこともなく
and end up rotting away
just like that!
ズルズルと腐ってゆく
その点 カイジ君は すばらしい
In that respect,
Kaiji is wonderful.
He's someone that I
look upon.
わしが見込んだ男じゃ やはり
命の使いどころというものを
心得ておる
He understands how to
make use of his life!
Just as you said,
まさしく 君の言うとおり
今は つかむか死ぬかのときなのだ
it is now the time to grab
the chance, or die!
そ そんな…
めちゃくちゃだ
N-No way...
This is insane.
雑魚には分からん
Commoners like you
won't understand.
ただ生きたいだけの雑魚にはな
You only care about
surviving.
受けよう
カイジ君の生き死にの ばくち
I'll accept it!
Kaiji's life-or-death gamble!
カイジさん
Kaiji.
Yeah.
払えよ 俺が勝ったら
You'd better pay up!
Pay me the 9 million if I win!
きっちり 900万
そして 謝るんだ
Then you have to apologise!
死んでいった仲間たちに
Apologise to my dead comrades.
利根川　お前が！
Tonegawa, you have to!
安心したまえ　わしに二言はない
Not to worry, I won't
go back on my word.
I will pay you the money
if you win.
カイジ君が勝てば ちゃんと払う
Then I'll make Tonegawa
apologise.
そして 利根川に謝らせよう
土下座でも何でもさせてな
I'll even make him
kneel down.
フフフ… おい そっちの準備もな
Hey, go get the
preparations now!
Yes!
Well then, Kaiji.
では カイジ君
安心して挑みたまえ
Just relax and take up
the challenge.
If you win, you'll get your
revenge and 20 million!
勝てば 無念を晴らし 2000万
However...
ただし…
負ければ…
If you lose...
You will die!
死ぬ！ハハハ…
Hey, clean that up.
おい 何か拭くものを
Yes!
Tonegawa!
利根川
Take off your watch!
時計を外せ
I'll keep it for you until
this battle is over.
この勝負が終わるまで
預かっておく
Is a paper towel all right?
ペーパータオルですが…
何でもかまわん
Anything will do!
Now then...
では…
You may begin!
始めたまえ
The final E-Card battle.
Ｅカード 最終戦
生死を賭けたオーラスが始まる
The life-or-death gamble has
finally begun!
１枚目は皇帝の利根川から
It begins with Tonegawa on
the Emperor side.
This is the first game
that he's serious about.
利根川にとって
この最終戦 初めての真剣勝負
ここまでの利根川は
腕時計に仕組まれた
Up to this point, he relied on
his watch to play his card.
計器を頼りに カードを出してきた
勝負をするふりをしてきた
だけである
He has been pretending
all this while.
However, this final battle
is different.
しかし この最終戦は違う
頼みの計器は ない
He doesn't have his
trusted watch.
あくまで 己の読み 勘
He has to rely on his
own judgement,
そして 運で
勝利をもぎ取るしかない
intuition, and luck to win!
It's a life-or-death match with
no room for mistakes!
まごうことなき 真剣勝負
Tonegawa has an overwhelming
advantage as the Emperor.
皇帝側である利根川は 圧倒的有利
However, he can't afford to
lose at all!
だが 逆に言えば負けられない
If he loses the game,
it won't be an easy escape.
負ければ
ただではすまないということ
それは誰よりも
利根川自身が分かっている
Tonegawa is more aware of that
than anyone else.
負けられない…
I cannot lose...
I have to win!
勝つ　それしかない
I have overcome various
difficulties so far.
わしは今まで幾多の苦境を
勝つことによって越えてきた
I just need to win.
勝てばいいだけのこと
[Slave]
それで 先ほどの不覚も埋め合わせ
That will make up for my
earlier failure,
and let me regain
the director's trust.
会長の信頼も回復できる
I must win!
勝つ！
I will win...
and kill this brat!
勝って この餓鬼を殺し…
I will survive!
生き残るのだ
I have nothing to fear!
この わしが
If I'm able to gauge when his
emotions are shaking,
恐れることはない
慎重に やつの感情のブレ
I can win the game easily!
濃い薄いを計れば勝てる
I can use the Emperor for the
second or third rounds.
後出しの２枚目か４枚目に
勝負を賭けて皇帝を出すか
市民を出し続け
Or I can continue with
Citizen cards,
and let him destroy himself
with his Slave card.
相手が奴隷カードを出して
自滅するのを待つ
That should be the way.
それが常法
何も１枚目で
勝負に行くことはない
There's no need to end the battle
with the first card.
No, in that case I should go
いや だからこそ逆に１枚目
I'll hit him on his blind spot
while he's unaware!
常法の裏をかき
盲点をついた不意打ち
I should play it as
the first card!
１枚目なのだ
Well then...
これで…
If he used the Emperor card,
this bet would be much easier!
これで 皇帝を出せたら
どれほど ばくちは楽か
いや そう単純ではないのだ
No! It's not so simple!
What if he read my intention of
launching a surprise attack?
もし 今わしが考えた不意打ちを
こいつに読まれたとしたら…
逆をついて やつは
奴隷を出してくるかもしれん
He might counter that by
using the Slave card.
どうした？
いつまで時間をかけるつもりだ
What's wrong?!
How long are you going
to drag?!
ビクビク ノロノロと…
You're so slow and timid!
That's why the old man has
given up on you!
そんなざまだから
会長のじじいに見限られる
You're merely someone
who waits for instructions!
指示待ち人間なんて言われるんだ
ぬう…
くっ こいつ…
T-This guy...
This brat!
この餓鬼が
I'll kill you, I'll kill you!
殺す　殺す
ぶっ殺す！
I'll kill you!
No.
いや 落ち着け
I must calm down.
これこそ やつの手かもしれん
This might be part of his plan.
It's his plan to make me
go for this.
あおって わしに勝負をさせる腹…
挑発に乗るのは危険だ
I shouldn't fall into
his trap!
Tonegawa finally plays his
first card!
利根川 ようやく１枚目を提出
受けて カイジ
即座に１枚目を提出
Kaiji responds immediately with
his first card!
両者オープン
Both sides open!
Citizen against Citizen!
市民と市民
カイジ 一歩 利根川を追い詰める
Kaiji closes the gap with
Tonegawa by one step!
Another step into
the abyss!
奈落へと
出せないだろ？
むう…
You couldn't use it here,
right?
フッ 分かっていても
You just couldn't use the
Emperor as your first card!
なかなか１枚目に
皇帝は出せやしない
皇帝は有利だっていう
余裕があるうちは
Although the Emperor has
the advantage,
いろいろ考えたあげく
結局 保険を打ってくる
you'd go for the safer option
after some consideration.
お前は まだまだ様子を見てるだけ
むう…
You're just watching
and waiting...
びびりながらな
...while quaking in fear!
So all I have to do
is to move forward!
その点 俺は ただ行くだけ
ん？こ こいつ…
T-This fellow!
ごみの分際で開き直りおって
This piece of trash
is being defiant.
失うもののない くずは
こうやって すぐ開き直る
People like him with
nothing to lose...
...tend to be defiant
very quickly.
だが わしは違う
However, I am different.
お前のようなカスと違って
積み上げてきたんだ
Compared to you trash,
I have made my way up...
何十年と
...for decades!
命知らずに負けて
消えるわけには いかんのだ
I can't be reckless and
let it all disappear before me!
勝たなければ…
I have to win...
I have to win!
勝たなければ… ん？
What is that?
あれは何だ？
That stain on the corner.
あのカードの汚れ…
I see...
そうか…
あのときの…
It was from just now.
That stain mark was
left behind.
拭いた跡… 拭き残しか
待てよ…
Wait a minute.
That means, the cards with
blood stains were...
ということは
あのとき 血がかかったカードは…
11戦で使った２枚
...the two cards used
in the 11th round!
使わなかった３枚は
The three unused cards
were left on his lap,
既に やつの膝の上に置かれていて
血は かからなかった
so they weren't stained.
In other words,
つまり あのカードは
11戦で使われた市民か奴隷
those cards were used in the
11th round.
The Citizen and the Slave!
２分の１の確率で
奴隷ということだ
There is a 50% chance that
one of them is the Slave.
Good.
しめた　思わぬ隙
It's an unexpected opening!
利根川 当然 市民を選択
Of course, Tonegawa uses
the Citizen card.
Come on, Slave!
来い 奴隷
２枚目オープン
They opened the cards!
だが 市民
But, it's a Citizen!
２枚目も引き分け
The 2nd round is also
a draw!
ということは…
So that means...
次に 汚れの付いたカードが来たら
When the next stained card
comes along,
必然的に残った１枚
it'll be the remaining one.
The Slave card.
つまり 奴隷
フフフ… 奴隷なのだ
It's the Slave!
I can win!
勝てる　勝てるぞ
I can survive!
生き残りだ
If I wait for him to play the
stained card,
血の付いたカードが
出るのを待って
この市民を出せば…
then use my Citizen card...
I can win!
勝てる　勝って生き残る
I can win and survive!
Wait!
待て　よく考えてみれば…
Come to think of it,
いくら市民のカードに
血痕が残っていたとはいえ
even though the Citizen card
had a stain...
It doesn't mean that the
Slave card was stained as well.
奴隷にも付いているとは限らない
The stain on the Citizen card
was left after wiping, after all.
市民カードに残った血は
あくまで拭き残し
The blood on the Slave card may
have been wiped off completely.
奴隷カードの血は
きれいに拭き取られたかもしれん
What an idiot.
ばかが　何を浮かれている
Why am I so happy?
確証などない
I can't be sure!
血痕が残っているか どうか
He can't be sure that the
other card was stained as well.
その両方の可能性を
捨てきることはできない
That's why he's hesitating.
そのことが 利根川をためらわせた
For the third round, Tonegawa from
the Emperor side plays first.
３枚目 皇帝の利根川の先出し
There's no proof that the
stained card is the Slave card!
奴隷カードに
血痕が残っている確証はない
だが 同時に血痕が
残っていないとも言い切れない
But, nobody can tell if there's
no stain on the card.
３枚目 勝負
The cards are opened!
Citizen and Citizen!
It's a draw!
市民と市民　引き分け
This has happened three times!
みたび繰り返される均衡
Before they knew it,
it's the 4th round...
気が付けば４枚目　すなわち…
...which is the final round.
最終選択
イヒヒ…
Kaiji's turn to begin.
４枚目は カイジの先出し
It's a 50-50 chance.
確率50％
A choice between
life-or-death.
生死を分ける二者択一
Heaven or hell.
天国か地獄
生還か破滅かを決す 最終選択
A final choice to determine
survival or destruction!
死ね
Die!
死んでもいい
It's okay even if
I die!
I must put myself aside and
just go for it!
自分を捨て 行け
運命の１枚
This is the card of fate!
There's no blood stain!
ない　血痕が
やはり 拭き取られてしまったのか
As expected, the stain was
wiped off.
それとも 残りの１枚が…
Or could it be the
last card?
おおっ 来た　血痕
There it is, the blood stain!
奴隷が
It's the Slave!
ハハハ… 勝ち
I will win!
I'll kill the Slave with
my Citizen and win!
この市民で 奴隷を殺して勝ち
You'll die soon!
死ぬ お前は
耳をそぎ落とした その気迫
その胆力は すさまじかった
Your courage in sacrificing
your ear was fantastic.
褒めてやる
I commend you for that.
But you brought this
massive bleeding upon yourself!
しかし 結局は
その大量出血が あだ
墓穴を掘ることになったな
You dug your own grave!
死ね
Die!
Just as he laid down his card,
doubt entered his mind!
カードを提出する直前
利根川の脳裏に浮かんだ疑念
He doubted that Kaiji
would overlook this.
果たして カイジは
気付かないだろうか？という疑問
自ら相手に手の内を
知られるような致命的ミス
He wouldn't make the mistake
of revealing his card.
この血痕に カイジが気付かない
そんなことが あり得るだろうか？
He doubted that Kaiji would
not notice the blood stain.
ましてや この血
カイジ自身が まき散らし
Furthermore, Kaiji was the one
who bled on the cards...
自分で拭き取ったもの
...before wiping them.
当然 拭き残しという可能性も
承知しているはず
Of course he knew it's possible to
leave stains on his cards.
How could he simply
leave stains like that?
その上で 残った血痕を
見逃しているというのか？
ありえん　こいつほどの男は
That's impossible!
For a man like him,
いくら耳を切り落とした激痛を
伴っているとはいえ
no matter how much pain he's
suffering from losing his ear,
見過ごすなど考えられん
he wouldn't have
overlooked this!
この勝負 やつにとっては
遊びではない
This match isn't just
a game to him.
命懸け　負ければ死が待っている
He bet his life on it.
He will die if he loses!
血の拭き残しなど
He'd have obsessively checked
for any blood stains left!
それこそ
神経質にチェックするはずだ
絶対にありえんミスだ
He wouldn't make
such a mistake!
ざわ… ざわ… ざわざわざわ…
With that in mind, he might
use the stained cards...
そう考えると
血痕の付いたカードが
わしが後出しの２枚目 ４枚目で
出てくるというのも出来すぎ
...for the second
and fourth rounds.
It's strange enough that he
bet 18 mm in this final battle.
そもそも この最終戦に
18ミリ勝負を挑むということ自体
異常な決断
[Slave, Emperor]
奴隷での勝負で何の勝算もなく
There's no chance of
winning with the Slave.
狂気じみた勝負に出るはずがない
He wouldn't attempt
something so absurd.
盛ったな？
You've poisoned it!
この勝負に毒を
You've poisoned this match.
間違いなく わなを仕掛けた
It's obvious that
he laid a trap!
この餓鬼
This brat...
He has a plan, and he's just
waiting for the chance.
何か策を打ち その上で待っている
わしの失策　うかつな決断を
Waiting for me to make a
mistake, a careless decision.
フフフ… 見かけによらず この男
Regardless of his appearance,
this man is a deceitful snake!
人をだまし食らう蛇よ
勝つためには手段を選ばぬ
卑劣な やから
He would do anything to win.
ものを言わず近づいて
背後から刺す非道 冷血
He'd silently stab someone
in the back.
He's cold-blooded!
In other words, he left
those blood stains on purpose.
ということは…
あの血痕は故意に残したもの
That's his strategy, his trap!
やつの戦略 わな
血を拭き取った後に
改めて付けた目くらましか？
It's a diversion he used
after wiping off the blood.
いや あくまで血は
No, he had to make it look
like the stains still remained.
拭き残したように
見せなければならん
片手しか自由の利かぬやつが
下手に小細工の動きをすれば
With only one free hand,
if he had tried any small move,
I wouldn't have let it slip by.
わしが見逃すわけがない
So, it was leftover from
the last time after all.
やはり あのときの拭き残し
そうか　あのとき 既に
カードが すり替わっていたのか
I see.
He had already
swapped the cards then!
While I was distracted with
talking to the director,
わしが会長の話に
気を取られている隙に
やつは 手の中に
市民カードを仕込み…
he took the Citizen card
that was in his hand.
Then swapped it with the
Slave card on the table.
テーブルの上の
奴隷カードと すり替えた
出血は その後
He splattered the blood
after that!
あのとき 血が付いたカードは
市民と奴隷ではなく
At that time, the stained cards
weren't Citizen and Slave,
２枚とも市民
but both Citizen cards!
That guy...
こいつ…
こんな とんでもないトリックを
He used such an
incredible trick.
この土壇場で ぬけぬけと
He's so impudent even
in these last moments!
なるほど…
I see...
This is possible for someone who
survived the Espoir and the bridge.
さすがは エスポワールや橋で
生き残っただけのことはある
つわものだ
He's a veteran.
しかし 残念ながら
However, it's too bad that you
won't be able to outwit me.
わしには
一歩 届かなかったようだな
イヒヒ…
フフフ… 惜しいな カイジ
It's too bad, Kaiji.
お前の盛った毒は漏れたぞ
The poison you put in
has leaked out.
なかなか見事な盛り方だったが
It was quite a smart way
of poisoning though.
But it didn't work on me
who avoid to swallow it.
服毒には至らず
わしは回避した
死ね　蛇が
Die, you snake!
これが とどめ
This is the end!
お前を殺す 鉄ついだ！
This is the iron hammer
that will kill you!
イヒヒ…
The final judgement has
finally been given.
ついに下される最終審判
カイジの前に開かれる扉は
生か？死か？
Will the door that is
opened for Kaiji...
...be the door of life,
or death?
Next, Enforcement.